A Finding Aid to the Lois Dodd Papers, 1945-2013, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Lois Dodd papers
1945-2013
Archives of American Art
Dodd, Lois, 1927-
AAA.doddlois
Archival Resource Key
6.82 Linear feet
The papers of New York City painter, educator, gallery owner, and activist Lois Dodd date from 1945 to 2013 and measure 6.82 linear feet. The papers focus on Dodd's personal work and contain little documentation of her involvement with Tanager Gallery. Found are biographical materials, including an interview conducted by Pat Mainardi in 1973; personal business records; professional correspondence; project and teaching files for Artist Housing Projects and various teaching positions; scattered writings and notes; printed materials including exhibition catalogs and announcements; and photographs. The 2014 and 2015 additions date from 1945-2013 and provide additional material related to Dodd's career as a painter and educator. Found here are biographical material; correspondence with friends and artists; writings by others; project and teaching files; personal business records; printed material; photographical material of artwork and Dodd; eleven travel sketchbooks; and a few pieces of artwork by George Schneeman.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Lois Dodd donated her papers to the Archives of American Art in several increments between 1981-2007. Dodd donated an additional 4.8 linear feet of material in 2014 and 2015.
Related Material
Among the collections of the Archives of American Art are the Tanager Gallery records, 1952-1972 and an oral history interview with Lois Dodd by Barbara Shikler conducted in 1988.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Lois Dodd (1927- ) is an observational painter, educator, activist, and co-founder of the Tanager Gallery. She is active in New York City and Maine.
Lois Dodd was born in 1927 in Montclair, New Jersey. Beginning in 1945, Dodd commuted from Montclair to New York City to attend The Cooper Union, from which she graduated in 1948. She married fellow student and sculptor William King with whom she had one child, Eli. King and Dodd, among others, established the Tanager Gallery in 1952.
Dodd worked for various organizations in New York City promoting affordable housing for artists, especially the renewal of Cooper Square. She continues to exhibit her paintings at both individual and group exhibitions.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of New York City painter, educator, gallery owner, and activist Lois Dodd date from 1945 to 2013 and measure 6.82 linear feet. The papers focus on Dodd's personal work and contain little documentation of her involvement with Tanager Gallery. Found are biographical materials, including an interview conducted by Pat Mainardi in 1973; personal business records; professional correspondence; project and teaching files for Artist Housing Projects and various teaching positions; scattered writings and notes; printed materials including exhibition catalogs and announcements; and photographs.
The 2014 and 2015 additions date from 1945-2013 and provide additional material related to Dodd's career as a painter and educator. Found here are biographical material; correspondence with friends and artists; writings by others; project and teaching files; personal business records; printed material; photographical material of artwork and Dodd; eleven travel sketchbooks; and a few pieces of artwork by George Schneeman.
Notable correspondents in the collection include Charles Cajori, Dave and Kathy Dewey, Lucien Day, Rackstraw Downes, William King, James L. Lentz, James McGarrell, Zalmar Perlin, Sidney Simon, Paul Smith, and Tom Wesselmann.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 7 series:
Missing Title
Series 1: Biographical Information, 1949-1989 (Box 1; 9 folders)
Series 2: Personal Business Records, 1950-1990 (Box 1; 0.1 linear feet)
Series 3: Correspondence, 1952-1991 (Box 1; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 4: Project and Teaching Files, 1969-1983 (Box 1-2; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 5: Writings and Notes, circa 1970-1990 (Box 2; 5 folders)
Series 6: Printed Material, circa 1970-2001 (Box 2; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 7: Photographs, 1952-circa 1990 (Box 2; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 8: Addition to the Lois Dodd Papers, 1945-2013 (Box 3-8; 4.8 linear feet)
Educators -- New York (State) -- New York; Painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Gallery owners -- New York (State) -- New York; Political activists -- New York (State) -- New York; Art -- Study and teaching; Women artists; Women educators; Women painters; Women art dealers; Artists' studios -- Photographs; Photographs; Interviews; Mainardi, Patricia
- Biographical Information, 1949-1989; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 9 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Found are records concerning awards, memberships, and certificates; biographical sketches and resumes; and personal materials including a driver's license from Maine, travel papers concerning Dodd's trip to Italy, and a transcript of a 1973 interview of Dodd by Pat Mainardi.
  - Awards, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Sketches, 1958-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificates, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Drivers License, Maine, before 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Membership Records, 1987-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
    (includes ribbon)
  - Resumes, 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Travel Papers, 1949-1960; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Interview Transcript, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Personal Business Records, 1959-1990; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 0.1 Linear feet Box 1
  Found are Lois Dodd's loan and exhibition agreements, contracts, donation records, gallery plans, lists, purchase orders, receipts, sales records, and shipping records. Also found is a file of correspondence and agreements for the publishing of Dodd's print Laundry.
  - Agreements, Exhibitions, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Agreements, Loans, 1982-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Concerning Laundry, 1990; 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Contracts, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Donations, Works of Art, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Donations, Monetary, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Gallery Plans, circa 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Price Lists, 1987-1990; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - List of Artists Exhibiting, 1968-circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Purchase Order, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Shipping Receipts, 1969-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Receipts, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Delivery Confirmation Receipts, 1976-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Sales Records, 1974-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Shipping Notes, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, 1952-1990; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 0.7 Linear feet Box 1
  Found are incoming and drafts of outgoing correspondence, the majority of which focuses on Dodd's painting career. Some personal correspondence may also be found. Notable correspondents include Lucien Day, Rackstraw Downes, James McGarrell, James Lentz, and Sidney Simon. Invitations to serve as art juror and to exhibit are found at the end of the series. Correspondence is also found in the project and teaching files.
  Arrangement note
  Correspondence is arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence, 1988; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 57-58)
  - Correspondence, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence, circa 1950s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Invitations, Art Juror, 1979-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Invitations, to Exhibit, 1979-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Postcards, 1988-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Project and Teaching Files, 1969-1983; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 1-2
  Project files concern Dodd's work with the five Artist Housing Projects, including the Cooper Square Renewal and one file concerning a mural at Citibank. Files contain corresondence, publicity materials, clippings, and drafts of writings. Teaching files include materials from Dodd's positions at Brooklyn College, City University of New York, the Cleveland Institute of Art, Colby College, Louisiana State Univeristy, the Skowhegan School of Painting, and the Vermont Studio School, and may include correspondence and financial materials.
  - Artist Housing Projects, Archival Resource Key (Box 1)
    - Cooper Square Renewal, 1969-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Cooper Square Renewal, Wyoming Building, 1972-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - "Museum,", 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Soho Lofts, 1969-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Westbeth, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Other Projects, Archival Resource Key (Box 1)
    - Citibank Mural, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Teaching Positions, Archival Resource Key (Box 2)
    - Brooklyn College, 1973-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - City University of New York, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Cleveland Institute of Art, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Colby College, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Louisiana State University, 1983-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Skowhegan School of Painting, 1979-1988; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
    - Vermont Studio School, 1984-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Writings and Notes, circa 1970-1990; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 5 Folders Box 2
  Scattered writings include a statement of plans by Dodd and a draft of a speech by Joe Fiori.
  - Statement of Plans, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Notes, Concerning Italian Grant, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Speech Notes, Joe Fiori, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Writings, circa 1970s-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Notes, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Printed Material, circa 1970-2001; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 2
  Printed materials include invitations, announcements, and catalogs for exhibitions of Dodd's work, including solo and group shows, as well as exhibitions of other artists. Also found are clippings, flyers, newsletters, and press releases. Of note are two publications featuring articles about and an interview with Dodd.
  - Invitations, 1977-1990; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Exhibition Announcements, circa 1970-1994; Archival Resource Key; 6 Folders (Box 2, Folder 16-21)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1981-2001; Archival Resource Key; 3 Folders (Box 2, Folder 22-24)
  - Auction Catalog, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Business Cards, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Blank Stationery, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, 1969-1988; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
  - Flyers and Info Sheets, circa 1970-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Magazine Articles About Dodd, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Newsletters, 1979-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Programs, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Press Releases, 1968-1990s; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
  - Italian Materials, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
    (Includes a blueprint of a ship and a pamphlet)
  - American Artist, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
    (Includes article on Lois Dodd by Laurie Hurwitz)
  - Bench Press Series on Ar t, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
    (Interviews with Bernadette Mayer and Lois Dodd)
- Photographs, 1952-circa 1990; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 2
  There are personal snapshots and professional portraits of Lois Dodd and of Dodd with Bill and Eli King, Ann Arnold, Lee Bontecon, Angelo Ippolito, and others. Also found are photos of Dodd with her artwork and in her studio, and of works of art by Dodd and others.
  - Lois Dodd, Portraits, 1965-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
    (Includes potraits in her studio)
  - Lois Dodd, Portraits, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
    (Includes potraits in her studio with works of art. Photos by Bob Brooks)
  - Lois Dodd and Bill King, circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Lois Dodd and Eli King, 1952-circa 1954; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
  - Lois Dodd, Lee Bontecon, Ann Arnold, by Mozette Tawil, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Lois Dodd and Angelo Ippolito, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Lois Dodd and Others, 1957-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Angelo Ippolito and Anita (no last name), 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Interior of Summer Studio, Cushing, Maine, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Auction, Cushing, Maine, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Works of Art, by Lois Dodd, circa 1960-1979; Archival Resource Key; 3 Folders (Box 2, Folder 50-52)
  - Works of Art, by Others, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Addition to the Lois Dodd Papers, 1945-2013; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 4.8 Linear feet Box 3-8
  Scope and Contents
  The 2014 and 2015 additions date from 1945-2013 and provide additional material related to Dodd's career as a painter and educator. Found here are biographical material; correspondence with friends and artists; writings by others; project and teaching files; personal business records; printed material; photographical material of artwork and Dodd; eleven travel sketchbooks; and a few pieces of artwork by George Schneeman.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged as 9 subseries
  Missing Title
  8.1: Biographical Material, 1949-2004 (Box 3; 4 folders)
  8.2: Correspondence, 1949-2000s (Box 3-5; 3 linear feet)
  8.3: Writings by Others, 1974-1980s (Box 6; 3 folders)
  8.4: Project and Teaching Files, 1965-2002 (Box 6; .4 linear feet)
  8.5: Personal Business Records, 1966-2000s (Box 6; .3 linear feet)
  8.6: Printed Material, 1945-2013 (Box 6; .3 linear feet)
  8.7: Photographic Material, 1950s-2000s (Box 7; .2 linear feet)
  8.8: Sketchbooks, 1986-1998 (Box 7-8; .6 linear feet)
  8.9: Artwork by Other Artist, 1981-1984 (Box 8; 1 folder)
  - Biographical Material, 1949-2004; 8.1; Archival Resource Key; 4 Folders Box 3
    Biographical material dates from 1949-2004 and is a certificate Dodd was awarded in weaving, an interview transcript, one notebook relating to a trip to Nova Scotia, and a resume.
    - Certificate in Weaving, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Lois Dodd Interview by Pat Mainardi, Transcript, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Notebook, "Trip to Cape Breton", 1988 June; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Resume, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1949-2000s; 8.2; Archival Resource Key; 3 Linear feet Box 3-5
    Correspondence dates from 1949-2000s and is primarily letters written to Dodd, both personal and professional in nature. Occasional drafts of Dodd's replies are also found here. Notable correspondents include Charles Cajori, Dave and Kathy Dewey, Lucien Day, William King, Zalmar Perlin, Paul Smith, and Tom Wesselmann. Personal letters are from friends and family and include holiday and greeting cards, postcards, and some photographs. Professional letters are from museums, galleries, and other arts organizations and institutions, including some relating to Tanager gallery. Mixed in are personal business records including loan agreements, shipping receipts, and payments records. Other professional letters relate to Dodd's environmental activism and housing advocacy for artists. Printed materials including exhibition announcements, newsletters, and flyers are found dispersed through the subseries.
    Arrangement reflects Dodd's original order. Correspondence was arranged chronologically in the 2014 addition and alphabetically by name in the 2015 addition.
    - By Name, Archival Resource Key (Box 3)
      - Lennart Anderson, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Tom Boutis, 1950-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Charles Cajori, 1950-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Jean Cohen, 2010; 1955-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Sally Hazelet Drummond, 1955-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Perle Fine, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Angelo Ippolito, 1962; 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Alex Katz, 1954-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - William King, 1949-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - K, Miscellaneous, 1950s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Arthur McTaggart, 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Tom O'Donnell, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Bob and Terry Sowers, 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Shirley Zimmerman, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1950s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1972-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1975-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 31-32)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 5-7)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
    - Chronological Correspondence, 2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Postcards, 1950s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Writing by Others, 1974-1980s; 8.3; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders Box 6
    Writings by others date from 1974-1980s and are artist statements by George Sugarman, Al Held, and Edith Schloss. Also found here is one student paper.
    - Artists' Statements, 1987; 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Student Paper, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Project and Teaching Files, 1965-2002; 8.4; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 6
    Project and teaching files date from 1965-2002 and relate to the Cooper Square housing renewal project, exhibitions Dodd curated and participated in, National Academy activities, and teaching appointments. Exhibitions include three that Dodd held in her Blairstown, New Jersey home (304 High Street). Items found here are price lists, press releases, notes, printed material, and correspondence. National Academy files reflect Dodd's service as council member, and are reports, minutes, memos, mailings lists, and printed material. Teaching files are from appointments at Queens College and Brooklyn College and include correspondence, memos, class schedules, handouts, curriculum vitae, and grant applications for exhibitions on campus.
    - Artists' Housing, Cooper Square Committee, 1972-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 3)